hello and welcome to the eighth tutorial
on how to program in g-script two
now in the past
all my tutorials
anytime i'd make a variable it always
just be the name of the variable and
then what it's equal to well you usually
don't want to do that
usually you're going to want to define
what type of variable your variable is
to do this
you type in whatever you want the value
to be then dot and then yellow or
whatever the name of your variable is
basically what this means
is that
this variable
is kind of attached to the npc
so in all the functions
all the kind of functions there are
yellow will always be the same
so here's an example
you always want to
show what type of variable it is in the
beginning it when you first define it
like that
so
i'm going to save now
and upload it
now when i say something hi it'll say
five
now now the second variable is
well that's it for the this dot variable
and now the next year i'm going to show
you is the temp dot variable
this variable will delete itself once
the function is has finished running
so for example
um
equals
temp dot yellow
this
will
work for anything
in the current function
but if i you if i try to try it in a
different function
like this
and i put this dot chat is equal to
temp dot yellow
then
it just won't work because it doesn't
know what yellow is because the yellow
has deleted itself
once it finished this function
so i'm going to save it
i'm going to say hi
and it'll just say zero because it
doesn't know what else to put
because
yellow doesn't really equal anything
here but if i have to call it again
like this
hi
so i think that's it for this tutorial
i'm going to get into
more detail on the other variables next
tutorial but these are two really simple
ones right now so anyway bye